Michael Moawad

michaelmoawad.com michaelmoawad.com

Efficient self-starter with 5 years building a solid foundation of technical knowledge and collaborative relationships within the Tech industry. Reduced time-to-value on critical new skill sets by rapidly mastering and adopting new technology stacks across frontend and backend environments, frameworks, and testing tools. 7+ years of experience collaborating with cross-functional colleagues on internal and external teams.

Technical Skills

Programming Languages: JavaScript, TypeScript | C#, PHP, Python | Bash, Git
Frameworks and Databases: React, Redux | NodeJS, RESTful API, jQuery | SASS, Tailwind | MySQL, PostgreSQL
Tools and Software: AWS, Docker, Linux VPS | Magento 2, WordPress | SSH/SFTP, Lighthouse, BrowserStack

Experience

Software Developer

Evinox - Sustainable Heat Networks

June 2023 - Present

- Designed and built fully responsive dashboards with dynamic data visualisations and stakeholder-specific journeys from scratch, leveraging component-based architecture, state-driven visual indicators, and threshold-based efficiency metrics to improve diagnostics and drive new revenue features.
- Employed **Redux** for seamless data flow and synchronisation, handling complex states (transactions, diagnostics, authentication), significantly boosting site performance and user experience.
- Engineered dynamic file validation in .NET, mapping Excel/CSV data to PostgreSQL via project matching, MPR checks, and relational queries, eliminating **95%** of manual fuel data errors.
- Redesigned user authentication by migrating token management from AWS services to Redux and local storage, enabling backend-driven authentication, supporting multiple user profiles per account, and reducing AWS costs by deprecating unnecessary front-end service dependencies.
- Assisted in reducing **AWS** monthly service costs by **80**% through efficient code refactoring and database indexing. Created pipelines to establish **CI/CD** environment while leveraging Lambda and EventBridge for scheduled tasks.

Front End Developer

Architectural Association

Nov 2020 - June 2023

- Developed **React** components able to retrieve and render information from live databases dynamically, allowing
 employees to independently upload content directly to site via **Statamic** CMS hugely reducing publishing time.
- Designed logic to map through, print data sets called from API's replacing 500+ lines of hard code across codebase.
- Process, manipulate and print pulled data using MySQL, PHP and Axios with NodeJS to access and handle JSON.
- Optimised code delivery and testing using Test-Driven Development (**TDD**) in conjunction with testing tools such as Inspector and Lighthouse.

Creative Projects

Bible Reader Web App React, Axios, CSS Flex, Netlify **Roll the Dice App** JavaScript, HTML, CSS

https://biblereader.netlify.app/ http://roll-the-dice-game.netlify.app/

Education

University of Southampton BEng (Hons) in Mechanical Engineering. 2:1

Sep 2015 - Jun 2018

Achievements & Interests

Music: Gained over 2 million streams with over 800 thousand monthly listeners and was placed on Spotify editorial playlists for tracks I wrote, recorded, produced, and mixed while building relationships with industry professionals. **Charity**: Co-Organiser for Coptic City Mission Fundraisers and Christmas parties, leading worship music and distributing foods and goods. Victoria, London.